Let's talk about how a series of daily price values arises.
我们来看看一系列每日价格的价值是如何上升的
It has to do with our earlier discussion of compounding.
它与之前讨论的复利有关
Let's say, a stock starts at P sub zero,
假设股价一开始是 p_0
and each day the price changes by some small percent, the return.
每天的价格都以很小的百分比变化 即收益率
We saw earlier how the price at time T could be written
我们之前了解到 在时间 t 的价格可以写成
as a product of all of these one plus little r sub i terms.
所有这些 (1 + r_i) 项的乘积
Remember, one plus little r equals P sub t divided by P sub t minus one.
注意 1 + r = p_t/(p_t-1)
If we take the log of both sides of this equation,
如果对等式两边都取对数
we get log of P sub t on one side and
左边变成 log(p_t)
a sum of log of one plus little r sub i terms on the other side.
右边变成 log(1+r_i) 项的和
Here, for convenience, I'm going to move log of P sub zero back to the left-hand side.
为了便于计算 我将 log(p_0) 移到左边
Remember, P sub zero is a constant,
注意 p_0 是一个常数
it's not dependent on time.
不随时间而变化
Now, we're going to use the central limit theorem.
现在我们将使用中心极限定理
You might remember the central limit theorem from a class on probability,
你可能还记得概率论课程中的中心极限定理
but if you don't I'll just explain it briefly here.
如果不记得 我简单解释下
It says that, the sum of random variables that
大量分布相同
have the same distribution and are not dependent on each
并且相互独立的随机变量之和
other approaches a normal distribution and
会收敛于正态分布
the limit that the number of random variables and the sum goes to infinity.
并且极限是随机变量的数量及和达到无穷大
So, let's make the assumption that the returns on each day are independent,
假设每日收益率相互独立
but come from the same underlying distribution.
但来自相同的分布图
This seems reasonable certainly more reasonable for returns and for prices.
这种假设是合理的 收益率和价格更合理
After all, the price of a stock on one day
毕竟一天的股价
almost certainly depends on its price the day before.
几乎肯定取决于前一天的股价
So, if we make that assumption,
如果这么假设的话
we can see that the right hand side,
可以看到右边总体来说
the wholesome is a random variable that follows a normal distribution.
是一个遵守正态分布的随机变量
So, we have that log of P sub t minus log of P sub zero is distributed normally.
所以 p_t-p_0 的分布是正态的
But if P sub 0 is a constant,
但如果 p_0 是常数
then log of P sub t is also distributed normally,
那么 log(p_t) 也是正态分布
because a normally distributed random variable minus
因为正态分布的随机变量减去常数
the constant is still normally distributed.
依然是正态分布
Now, I'm going to tell you about a new distribution called the log-normal distribution.
现在我将介绍一种新的分布 叫做对数正态分布
Guess what, it looks kind of like that right-skewed distribution we talked about earlier.
看起来与我们之前讨论过的右偏态分布有点像
What you need to know about the log normal distribution is that if Y is
对于对数正态分布 你需要知道的是
distributed normally then e to the y is distributed log normally.
如果 Y 是正态分布 那么 e^Y 是对数正态分布
I'll say that again, if Y is distributed normally,
再强调一次 如果 Y 是正态分布
then e to the y is distributed log normally.
那么 e^Y 是对数正态分布
So, if log of P sub t is distributed normally,
如果 log(p_t) 是正态分布
then P sub t which equals e to the log of P sub t is distributed log normally.
那么 p_t（等于 e^log(p_t)）是对数正态分布
In fact, prices are frequently assumed to arise from a log normal distribution.
实际上 股价经常是对数正态分布
This seems reasonable from just eyeballing the distribution
观察分布图后 发现似乎是这样的
because we can see that it doesn't go below zero and it's skewed to the right.
因为我们知道它不会低于 0 并且向右偏态
Those properties match our actual price distribution well.
实际价格分布完全表现出这些特性
However, when working with real data,
但是 在处理实际数据时
the assumption that prices are distributed log normally,
股价呈对数正态分布这个假设
may or may not be a good one.
可能是好的假设 也可能不是
These distributions can be convenient models,
这些分布也许是很方便的模型
but don't confuse them with actual distributions of stock prices or returns.
但是不能当做实际股价或收益率分布